# **CANDICE HADDAD**

- ☑candice.haddad@gmail.com ② cjhaddad.github.io ୯ 3179858281 ♀ Chicago, IL
- 🛩 candicehaddad in candicehaddad 🖸 cjhaddad

### **ABOUT ME**

I firmly believe that software and technology can and does make significant impacts on people's quality of life. As an academic researcher turned developer, I aim to build meaningful, rich software that emphasize empathy and usability.

#### **SKILLS**

Ruby, Ruby on Rails, Javascript (jQuery, AJAX), HTML, CSS, Sqlite, PostgreSQL,

TDD (RSpec, Jasmine, Capybara), Sinatra, Git, Heroku, Activerecord, Object-Oriented Design,

Agile Development

## **EXPERIENCE**

Jun 2014 to Current	Chicago Chapter Co-Founder/ City Director $\cdot$ Women Who Code $\cdot$ Chicago, IL $\circ$ Organize educational events for women learning to code
Feb 2015 to Jun 2015	Web Development Student · Dev Bootcamp · Chicago, IL  · Learned web development skills during a 19-week immersive program  · Co-developed LET'S, a mobile-first, group decision-making web app that uses Ruby on Rails, Javascript (AJAX, jQuery), and background-processing gem Sidekiq.  · Co-developed Reach Out, a crisis response app, that uses Ruby, Sinatra, and Twilio API.
Aug 2012 to Jan 2015	Ph.D. Researcher · University of Michigan · Ann Arbor, MI  · Conducted ethnographic research on how Arab American youth consume and produce media · Interviewed over 45 people · Collected and analyzed data for dissertation titled Being Young in Arab Detroit: Media and Identity in Post-9/11 America
Jun 2014 to Jan 2015	Grant Program Evaluator · Arab American National Museum · Ann Arbor, MI  O Contract position to analyze impact of museum's use of four-year W.K Kellogg Foundation Grant  Wrote evaluation report based off of program documents and participant interviews and feedback
Sep 2010 to Jan 2015	Graduate Student Instructor · University of Michigan · Ann Arbor, MI  · Assisted instruction of courses on: digital media; media, culture, and society; media industries,  · Led instruction and designed courses on: mass media; digital media and identity.
Aug 2013 to Jan 2014	Project Manager · Program on Intergroup Relations, University of Michigan · Ann Arbor, MI  · Lead team of 10 students to qualitatively and quantitatively analyze data from an undergraduate course on Arab-Jewish dialogues  · Facilitated student discussions around Arab-Jewish relations

#### **EDUCATION**

2014	University of Michigan, Ann Arbor Ph.D. Communication Studies
2009	University of Texas at Austin M.A. Media Studies
2006	Indiana University, Bloomington B.A. Communication and Culture